nmh.org 2003-06-21

# Northwestern Memorial Website Privacy Statement

  |   
---|---  
  |    
  | **Introduction/Commitment**  
  | As an academic medical center where the patient comes first, Northwestern Memorial is committed to protecting the privacy of all visitors to its website. It is our goal to maintain compliance with the highest standards of website privacy so our visitors may comfortably and safely use the site for a range of healthcare information needs. As used here, "Northwestern Memorial" means Northwestern Memorial Hospital and where appropriate, its affiliated and parent organizations.  
  |    
  | **What Information We Collect**  
  | Our system routinely collects information about origin and site navigation of website visitors. This information is used only to help us continually modify the site based on use patterns and is not linked to any personal identifying information. We do not collect any identifying or personal data on site users unless that information is submitted as part of a request for service or information, such as requesting an appointment. Northwestern Memorial does not currently use "cookies." A "cookie" is a text file placed on the browser of website visitor to identify website use patterns.  
  |    
  | **Who Is Collecting The Information**  
  | The only people using aggregate website access information are Northwestern Memorial employees, in particular, our web team. If a visitor submits additional identifying information (as noted above), that information is available only to the Northwestern Memorial staff who will be involved in implementing the requested activity.   
  |    
  | **How We Will Use The Information**  
  | Information about website use patterns will be utilized by the web team and other appropriate Northwestern Memorial staff to modify and enhance the website. Identifying individual information (such as name, e-mail, and address) will be used only as requested by the visitor.  
  |    
  | **With Whom Will The Information Be Shared**  
  | Northwestern Memorial does not sell, share or release any information about website users to any third parties, unless requested to do so by that user. Personal information about individual website users, as submitted as part of a service or information request, will not be shared in any way without specific consent from the user. However, we may disclose information when legally compelled to do so.   
  |    
  | **Consumer Choices**  
  | 

Personal information about website users is collected only as part of a request for service. If information is required in order to provide a service, the website user will be informed as to which information in optional and which is essential for receipt of the service. Users have the option of asking that personal information be removed from our site once the service has been completed. Users also have the choice of ending any subscription or request for information by submitting a cancellation request to [webmaster@nmh.org](mailto:webmaster@nmh.org).

If users do not wish to have any "cookies" attached to their browser, they may disable cookies through their browser or Internet service company.   
  
  |    
  | **E-mail Security**  
  | The Northwestern Memorial website offers opportunities to communicate with some Northwestern programs by e-mail. Because normal e-mail is not encrypted, the possibility exists that unauthorized individuals may intercept e-mail messages with Northwestern Memorial. Northwestern Memorial is not responsible for privacy of e-mail messages except those stored in our system.  
  |    
  | **Links**  
  | 

Northwestern Memorial provides links to other sites.

Among them, Northwestern Memorial has contracted with HEALTH _vision_ for access to the LaurusHealth library of consumer health information. This information is stored on HEALTH _vision_ servers, and HEALTH _vision_ uses "cookie" technology to track aggregate use of its site. HEALTH _vision_ states in its privacy policy that it will maintain confidentiality of any and all personally identifying information it may gather.

Northwestern Memorial Hospital has also contracted with Photobooks, Inc. to manage the searchable physician directory. Photobooks uses "cookie" technology to track aggregate use of its site and states in its privacy policy that it will maintain confidentiality of any and all personally identifying information it gathers.

Users are encouraged to review the privacy policy of each linked site, as Northwestern Memorial is not responsible for the privacy policies or procedures of other sites.  
  
  |    
  | **Security Procedures/Access**  
  | Information sent by e-mail to Northwestern Memorial will be accessed only by Northwestern Memorial staff as necessary to complete the function requested by the website visitor. The servers on which we store information are kept in a secure environment, behind a locked door, and are protected electronically from access by unauthorized individuals.  
  |    
  | **Corrections**  
  | All information submitted to the Northwestern Memorial website may be reviewed and changed. In order to review or change your information, contact the Northwestern Memorial Webmaster at [webmaster@nmh.org](mailto:webmaster@nmh.org)  
  |    
  | **Notification of Changes**  
  | If Northwestern Memorial changes this privacy statement, we will post those changes on the website so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. Any such changes shall be effective as of the date they are posted on the website.  
  |    
  | **How to Contact the Web Team**  
  |  **_E-Mail_**  

**_Telephone_**  
312.926.4872

**_Fax_**  
312.926.0209

**_Mail_**  
Northwestern Memorial Web Team  
Northwestern Memorial Hospital  
240 East Ontario Street  
Suite 417  
Chicago, IL. 60611  
  
  |    
  |    
 UPDATED: 09-Apr-2003
